（政(せい)）
やっと着いたか　随分とかかったな
We've finally made it.
It took quite a while.
So... that's...?
（貂(てん)）…てことは あれが？
（政）そうだ
Yes.
（政）あれが 秦国(しんこく)の王都 咸陽(かんよう)だ
That is the capital of the State of Qin. Xianyang.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）古代中国
Ancient China.
聖者の時代は終わりを告げ
人間の欲望は解放されていた
After learning that the era of saints had ended,
human desire was unleashed.
And a storm of violent wars erupted for 500 years...
戦乱の嵐が
500年にわたって吹き荒れ
100を超えた国々は
７つに淘汰(とうた)された
until over one hundred states were reduced to merely seven.
And now, a wind of great history gusts from the State of Qin in the far West.
そして今 西の果ての国 秦から―
大いなる歴史が
生まれようとしている
This is the tumultuous tale of a nameless boy and a young king who brought the warring era to its end!
これは
戦乱の時代を生き抜いた―
名もなき少年と若き王の
激動の物語である
（信(しん)）ンンッ！
Presented by Anime-Destiny
Translation
kewl0210
itsumo yori hayaku kietetta hoshi zora ni
いつもより早く消えてった星空に
In a starry sky that disappeared faster than it ever has
kusanariatta deai wa
重なり合った出会いは
the many piled up meetings we've had
Editing
jagman1x3
ore wo nomikonde iku
俺を呑み込んでいく
swallow me.
kono yume wa kudakenai
この夢は砕けない
This dream cannot be broken.
Timing
rtrs
sabitsukaseta kyoufushin
錆びつかせた恐怖心
Among this rusted fear in my heart
yuragu fuan no naka de
揺らぐ不安の中で
and the anxiety that makes me waver
Typesetting
rtrs
ame wo saegiru shinjitsu
雨を遮る信実
is a truth that interrupts the rain.
Karaoke
kewl0210
FZeroWing
dare ni mo ubaeyashinai
誰にも奪えやしない
No one can take it away,
onaji keshiki ni hisonda puraido
同じ景色にひそんだプライド
our pride that lurks in the same landscape.
Encode
max80
itsuka kitto kanau ima mo mieru kibou fortitude
いつかきっと叶う 今も見える希望 fortitude
The fortuitous desire I have will definitely come true one day.
yowasa wo sute wa shinai
弱さを捨てはしない
We won't throw away our weaknesses,
oretachi no kienai shiin
俺達の消えないシーン
those are scenes that won't disappear.
furenzokusen no youni hashiru kibou unbreakable heart
不連続線の様に走る希望 unbreakable heart
My desire in my unbreakable heart runs like a discontinuitous line.
I knew at the start that there's no end.
QC
Mistral[sA]
KoolKidsK
I've made up my mind, right now it's the time to take the first step.
Distro
kokus
Kittie
prefix-
Qpax
Now's the only time.
～♪
Invading the Royal Capital
Wh-What is that?
（信）えっ… 何だ？ ありゃ
でかすぎて 一体
何が何だか さっぱり分かんねえよ
It's way too gigantic! I haven't got a clue what anything is!
取り乱すな アホ！
Don't piss yourself, moron!
あんなもん 誰が どうやって？
何のために？ アア～ッ！
How- How the hell do you make something like that? And what for?!
（貂）落ち着け！
（楊端和(ようたんわ)）さすがだな
Calm down!
Just as I'd expect.
おい 政… 俺たち
今から あれに攻め込むのか？
Hey, Zheng, are we gonna go attack that thing?
Yes.
そうだ
How the hell do you attack something that huge?!
どうやって
あんなでかいもん 攻めるんだよ？
端が見えねえよ 端が！
I can't even see the other side!
Don't get flustered.
今更 騒ぐな
（信）えっ？
（政）奥に ひときわ大きな建物が
並んでいるのが見えるか？
Can you see the especially large building in the center?
Huh? Yeah, I see it.
（信）えっ？ ああ 見える
（政）あれが王宮だ
That's the royal palace.
（政）今回の反乱のことは
あの王宮の外には公にされていない
This rebellion has not been publicly announced outside of the royal palace.
つまり
外は 弟の陣営に染まっていない
Which means the outside has not yet joined my little brother's ranks.
Huh?! So you mean we've just gotta beat the people in the royal palace?!
（貂）…てことは
王宮だけ たたけばいいってこと？
That's right.
（政）そうだ
（信）ちょっと待て！
Hold on a second!
王宮って 咸陽の―
The royal palace is smack in the center of Xianyang!
ど真ん中にあるじゃねえか！
（政）当たり前だ
Of course.
Xianyang was built with the royal palace in the center, surrounded by many castle walls,
（政）咸陽は 王宮を中心に
何重もの城壁や―
and the dwellings of noble families, warrior families, and commoners.
貴族 士族 庶民の
住居が配置してある
つまり 咸陽自体が巨大な城なのだ
In other words, Xianyang itself is one giant castle.
Of course...?
（信）“当たり前”って…
How the hell are we gonna get through all that to get to the palace?!
そんな中を
一体 どうやって王宮まで…
Like we said, we've worked out a plan.
（昌文君(しょうぶんくん)）だから
策を講じると言っておろうが
Even if you've got a plan, besides those friggin' tall castle walls,
（信）策っつっても
あんな高(たけ)え城壁があるうえに―
中にゃ 大軍が控えてるんだろう？
they've got an army waiting for us inside!
That's our objective.
（昌文君）そこが狙い目だ
80,000, is it?
（竭氏(けつし)）８万か
（殴る音）
（肆氏(しし)）アッ…
That is not nearly enough, Shi Shi.
全然 足りぬではないか 肆氏よ
（肆氏）申し訳ありません
My humblest apologies. But seeing as we have yet to find the sovereign's seal,
いまだ玉璽(ぎょくじ)が見つからぬ状況では
この兵の数が精いっぱい
this was the largest number of soldiers we could muster.
You can gather soldiers without the sovereign's seal, can't you?!
（竭氏）玉璽などなくとも
兵は集まるだろう
買収でも脅しでも何でもよい
Use bribery, threats, whatever it takes!
こたびの乱を静観している有力者の
尻をたたき回れ！
Go spank the behinds of the influential men that are silently observing this revolt!
（竭氏）これは防衛戦ではない
（蹴る音）
This is not a defensive battle.
We have only one goal;
我らの目的は ただひとつ
呂軍(りょぐん)20万の殲滅(せんめつ)
to wipe out the Lü Army of 200,000 men!
For that, we require many, many more soldiers!
そのためには まだまだ兵が必要だ
Retrieve another 100,000 soldiers at once!
至急 あと10万の兵を起こせ
Do not disappoint me, Shi Shi.
わしを失望させるな 肆氏よ
（肆氏）はっ！
Yes, my lord.
80,000 is a little?
（信）８万じゃ少ねえのか？
By our original calculations, we expected no less than 400,000 soldiers.
（昌文君）最初の算段では―
40万ほどの軍を
起こすつもりだったはずだ
しかし
呼びかけに集まったのは８万
But when they called out for soldiers, they only gathered 80,000.
You can be sure that Jie Shi is very nervous.
内心 竭氏は焦っているに違いない
And then, a large band of people seeking to be his allies will come from a place he didn't expect.
そこに 思わぬ所から
味方となる大軍が現れる
Us?
俺たちか
（政）そうだ
Yes. We'll make him think we're allies. And if he invites us into the royal palace...
味方と思わせ
王宮まで招き入れさせれば…
We will have overcome the castle walls unscathed.
俺たちは無傷で城壁を越えられる
Now, let's go!
さあ 行くぞ！
（見張り）
うん？ ウワッ！ あれは…
Those are...!
（政）いよいよだ
Finally.
楊端和
共に戦ってくれることを感謝する
Yang Duan He, you have my deep gratitude for fighting with us.
Words of gratitude are something to be said after victory.
感謝の言葉は
勝利のあとに言うものだ
（政）勝利のあとは 言葉ではなく
城を挙げて 山の民を歓待する
After our victory, it won't be with words. It will be by giving a castle and a friendly welcome to you Mountain People.
（楊端和）期待しておくぞ
I'll be looking forward to it.
A crowd of Mountain People have appeared at the West Gate?!
（竭氏）
西の門に 山の民の群れが―
現れただと？
（江(こう)）はっ！
Yes, my lord!
（竭氏）数は？
（江）2,000から3,000です
Their number?
2,000 to 3,000.
They came on horseback wearing odd outfits and carrying weapons.
皆 異様な姿で騎馬し
武器を持っております
しかし
攻撃してくる様子はないとのこと
Though they do not seem to be here to do battle.
Was there no messenger?
使者のような者は来なかったのか？
（江）はい
There was. He informed us that the Mountain King has descended the mountains in order to reform an alliance.
“山の王が盟を復活させるべく
下山してきた”とだけ告げ
He then returned to the crowd.
群れに戻ったそうです
The Mountain King... seeks an alliance...?!
（竭氏）山の王が 盟を…
いきなり
８万の大軍が躍り出てきたりしてな
I'll bet an army of 80,000 are suddenly gonna come prancing out.
Why do you always say stuff like that?
どうして
お前は そういうこと言うかな
大丈夫だ　ヤツらは必ず乗ってくる
It's all right. They're sure to take the bait.
That'd be nice...
（信）…だといいがな
With the deciding battle with Lü Shi approaching,
（役人１）
呂氏との決戦が近づいたこのときに
味方が増えるのは ありがたい
we should be grateful to gain any allies!
（役人２）3,000ではあるが
あの馬酒兵(ましゅへい)の血を引く者たちなら
It may be only 3,000,
but if the blood of those Majiu Soldiers is flowing through their veins,
大きな戦力になる
（迫氏(さこし)）待て！
they'll be a force to be reckoned with!
Wait!
長年 絶縁していたヤツらが
なぜ突然 盟の復活などと？
After having cut all ties with us for all these years, why would they suddenly revive the alliance?!
何か たくらんでおるに
決まっておろうが
It's obvious that they're scheming something!
But they're already at the castle gate! What do we do?!
（役人２）だがヤツらは
もう 城門まで来ておる
どうするのだ？
（迫氏）山猿などと
手を組めるか！
There's no way we can ally with those mountain monkeys!
３万ほど出して
皆殺しにすればよい
Just send out 30,000 men to kill them all!
（役人３）おお！ 呂軍との
対戦の前に いい軍事演習となるぞ
That will be a good training exercise before the battle with the Lü army.
They sure are taking a while!
遅(おせ)えな
They're opening it.
開くぞ
Greetings. Please come in.
（役人）どうぞ お入りください
秦国は あなた方を歓迎いたします
The State of Qin welcomes you.
You're inviting monkeys into the royal palace?!
（成蟜(せいきょう)）
猿どもを王宮に招き入れるだと？
What is this nonsense you've decided on without consulting me?!
この俺に相談もなく
何を勝手に決めておるのだ 貴様！
It is to form an alliance.
盟を結ぶためです
You did entrust all governing to me, so I went by my own judgement.
政(まつりごと)は全任するとのことでしたので
独断いたしました
If you are displeased with my decision, I beg your forgiveness...
お気に召されなかったのでしたら
どうか お許しを
しかし まずは―
But would the sight of the Lü Army fighting the Mountain People not be amusing?
呂軍と山の民が戦うサマを
眺めるのも 一興ではありませぬか
Using monkeys to fight a fox... is that right?
“たぬきには猿”というわけか
（竭氏）さようです
That is right.
（成蟜）
だが 俺は猿とは しゃべらんぞ
But I won't be speaking with any monkeys!
Sitting on the throne as the king of the State of Qin is sufficient.
秦国の王として
玉座にあられるだけで結構です
全て この丞相(じょうしょう)にお任せを
（成蟜）フン…
Leave everything to me, your chancellor...
Easy-peasy!
（信）ハハッ！ 楽ちん 楽ちん！
Things are going well so far.
（壁(へき)）
今のところは順調だ　しかし…
But...
the idea that we would have needed to break down all of these castle walls gives me the chills.
（壁）もし これだけ多くの城壁を
破らなければならなかったとしたら
寒気がする
You thought so, too, Brother Bi?
壁のあんちゃんでも そう思うか
当たり前だ　城攻めというのは
本来 ２倍から３倍の人数を要する
Of course.
Ordinarily, you need two to three times the enemy's number of men in order to attack a castle.
We're trying to do that with 3,000.
（壁）
それを 3,000で落とそうというのだ
This is truly a plan among plans.
正に 奇策中の奇策と言える
Really? I'm kinda fired up now!
（信）
そうなのか！ なんか燃えてきたぜ
張り切るのは いいが 油断するな
It's good to be enthusiastic, but don't let your guard down!
王宮の外とはいえ
敵地には変わりない
Though we may be outside of the royal palace, we're still on enemy ground.
I know.
分かってるよ
（貂）オッ？
Look, Xin! It's the city!
（貂）見ろよ 信　町だぜ
Something's odd.
（壁）何か変だ
（信）何がだ？ 壁のあんちゃん
What is it, Brother Bi?
It feels different from how Xianyang is normally. There's an odd tension in the air...
いつもの咸陽と
違う微妙な緊張感が漂っている
まさか 気づかれてんのか？
Do you think they found us out?
It's unlikely.
（昌文君）そうではなかろう
民衆の中をよく見てみよ
Take a good look at the people.
There are a lotta guys dressed in all black.
（信）黒ずくめが多いな
（壁）あれは“捕吏”だ
Those are police officers.
What're plicofficers?
（信）“ホリ”って何だよ？
（壁）罪人を召し捕る役人のことだ
People who apprehend criminals.
そうか… 王弟派の連中め
民衆の口を封じているのか
I see... Those who support the younger brother...
They're silencing the people.
（昌文君）成蟜の王位は あくまで
大王急死による正当なものであり
Chengjiao's claim to the throne is legitimate only if it's due to the king's sudden death.
反乱による略奪であってはならない
It cannot be due to stealing it through a rebellion.
王宮より漏れ出るよからぬウワサは
断固として封じなければならぬ
So they must firmly prevent any disparaging rumors from leaking from the royal palace.
According to reports, the ones who have spoken about the current events happening inside the palace
（昌文君）報告では
今 王宮について語った者は―
即座に 捕吏に捕まり
二度と家に戻ってこぬそうだ
have been immediately arrested by the police officers and barred from ever returning to their homes.
That's terrible...
ひでえ…
（政）まだまだ序の口だ
That's just the beginning.
成蟜も竭氏も
目的のためなら手段を選ばん
Chengjiao and Jie Shi will do anything to achieve their goals.
これは２人が行う圧政の
ごく一部にすぎまい
This is certainly nothing more than a small fraction of the tyranny those two are carrying out.
They're a bunch of monkeys.
（捕吏１）猿だ 猿！
（捕吏２）ハハハッ…
やめろよ　刺激するなって命令だぞ
Stop it. We've been ordered not to excite them.
Hey!
（左慈(さじ)）おい
（捕吏２）ああ？
（殴る音）
（左慈）ジャマだ！
You're in the way!
Hey! Do you think you're gonna get away with doing that to...
こら！
俺たちに こんなマネして ただで…
（捕吏１）じょ…
上級武官の左慈さまと魏興(ぎこう)さま
It-It's the top-class military officers, Lord Zuoci and Lord Weixing!
If they're following that man, that means...
そのお２人を
従えているということは…
あ… あのお方は
竭丞相さまの片腕 肆氏！
That man is Chancellor Jie's right-hand man, Shi Shi!
You should get lost.
（左慈）うせてよし
Y-Yes, sir! Excuse us!
（捕吏たち）
は… はい！ 失礼しました！
（魏興）たかが3,000の兵を
手に入れるために―
But to have to invite them inside the royal palace in order to gain 3,000 soldiers...
王宮まで招くとは
丞相は焦り過ぎではありませぬか？
Don't you think the chancellor is being hasty?
It is not 3,000.
（肆氏）3,000ではない
あれは山界の覇者 楊端和だ
That is the Mountain World King, Yang Duan He.
If we form an alliance with him, we'll be able to make allies of hundreds of thousands of Mountain People.
ヤツと盟を結べば
十数万の山の民を味方にできる
I see.
（魏興）なるほど
それを見越しての丞相の判断
So the chancellor made his decision, seeing through to that end.
But even so, one thing bothers me...
（肆氏）
それにしても ひとつ気にかかる
Why now?
なぜ今なのだ？
数百年 絶縁していて
なぜ今 急に…
After having no ties for hundreds of years, why would they suddenly...
アア… 手が汚れた
I got my hand dirty...
Here?
ここか？
（政）王宮だ
It's the royal palace.
It looks even bigger than it did from up on the cliff...
（信）崖の上で見たより でけえな
当たり前だけどよ
Guess you've gotta expect that, though.
どうした？ おじけづいたか？ 政
（政）全ては ここから始まった
What's up?
Lose your nerve, Zheng?
Everything started here...
Inside the royal palace, Piao always used to talk about you.
（政）王宮の中で
漂(ひょう)は お前の話ばかりしていた
His eyes would light up as if showing us a treasure of his.
まるで 自分の宝物を
見せるかのように 目を光らせてな
The stories about the two of you training together.
２人だけの稽古の話
牛を馬代わりにして練習した話
Like when you used an ox in place of a horse for training.
Or about the dream the two of you had of becoming great generals...
そして ２人で誓った大将軍への夢
（信）将軍…
（漂）そうだ！
Generals?
Yeah! We'll wear golden armor and travel the world!
黄金の甲冑(かっちゅう)をまとって
大地を駆け巡り…
And finally, we'll become the greatest generals under the heavens!
ついには 天下の大将軍となる！
大将軍…
Great generals?!
And our names will go down in history?!
そして 歴史に名を残すのか！
If it weren't for Chengjiao's rebellion,
（政）成蟜の反乱がなければ―
漂にも お前にも
会うことはなかったわけだが
I would never have met you or Piao, but...
I suppose Piao would not have died, either...
やはり 漂が死ぬこともなかった
And the ringleaders who sparked the flame of that rebellion are inside here right now.
そして
反乱に火をつけた張本人たちは―
今 この中にいる
It's time to end this, Xin!
決着の時だ 信
（信）おう！
Right!
Even if we're wrong, don't die.
間違っても死ぬなよ
（信）俺が死ぬだと？
Me, die?
ヘヘッ…
天下の大将軍への第１歩だ
This is my first step towards being the greatest general under the heavens!
Like hell I'm gonna drop dead in a place like this!
…んなとこで こけるかよ！
（江）なにも丞相自ら出迎えずとも
よいではありませぬか
Even if you're not welcoming them in person, are you sure this is wise, Chancellor?
野人どもを相手に
Allowing those wild beasts in here...
（竭氏）バカ者が
江 お前は何も分かっておらん
You fool!
Jiang, you know nothing...
相手は楊端和なのだぞ
（江）はぁ？
This is Yang Duan He we're meeting with.
Though just a little, I have been personally trading with a portion of the Mountain People.
（竭氏）わしは 僅かだが 山の民の
一部と 私的に交易を行っている
They have many tribes.
彼らの種族は多い
Though of course, I did not know they would be descending the mountains at this time...
（竭氏）さすがに こたびの
下山のことは知らなかったが
しかし
山の王 楊端和のことは聞いている
But I have heard of the Mountain King, Yang Duan He.
He has a strong interest in the flatlands,
平地に強い興味があり
下山する機会を
うかがっていたそうだ
and has been seeking a chance to descend the mountains, it seems.
With Yang Duan He as king, the Mountain People have become more powerful than they ever have.
楊端和が王になり 山の民の力は
かつてより強まっている
今は その力が必要なときだ
And right now, we need that power...
（バジオウ）この先は
王と 使者50人までだそうだ
It seems they will only let the king and 50 envoys with her past this point.
50?!
50人？ たったの50人で
どうやって８万と戦うんだよ？
How the hell are we gonna fight 80,000 people with just 50?!
Calm down.
（政）騒ぐな　民兵を含む８万の
軍が王宮に入っているはずがない
The army of 80,000 made up of militia men will not be inside the royal palace.
軍の駐屯所は
ここより東に離れている
The army is stationed far to the east of here.
What? Why didn't ya say so?
（信）な～んだ 早く言えよ
だが 王宮の異変に気づけば
すぐに押し寄せてくるぞ
But if they notice any abnormalities inside the royal palace, they'll immediately send them to march on us.
We must defeat Chengjiao and Jie Shi before that happens.
そうなる前に
成蟜と竭氏を討たねばならん
Changwenjun! Bring forward the ten people who have knowledge of the inside of the royal palace.
（政）昌文君！
王宮内の知識がある者を10人出せ
（昌文君）はっ！
Yes, my king.
If a battle does start, should the people on the outside try to break down the gate?
（壁）戦が始まったら
外の者に 門を破らせましょうか？
In that case, the external enemy army will gather here.
それでは 外の敵軍が集まってくる
Unless we settle this inside the royal palace, we have no chance of victory.
（政）この戦 王宮内だけの
決戦にしなければ 勝ち目はない
So all those outside the gate will watch over all of the exits
だから 門の外の者たちは―
全ての出口を張り
外に出る者だけを捕らえろ
and capture anyone who goes outside.
I'll request that the other 40 to enter be Mountain People.
あとの40人は山の民で頼む
（バジオウ）分かった
Understood.
Hey! I'm going, too!
あっ 俺も行くぞ
（政）もちろんだ
Of course.
Why the hell are you tagging along?!
お前 なに ついてきてんだよ？
（貂）あいた！
Get the hell back there!
とっとと帰れ
（貂）今更 ムリだね
It's too late now.
Do you have any idea what's about to happen?!
（信）お前 今から何が起こるか
分かってんのか？
（貂）分かってるさ
Yeah, I do!
中が失敗したら どのみち
外にいても皆殺しになるんだ
If we lose in there, even if we're outside, we're all gonna get killed.
それに 外の連中の中じゃ
居場所がねえもん
And on top of that, I don't fit in with those guys outside.
Even though they saw the clothes I'm wearing, they didn't react at all.
（貂）あいつら 俺の格好を見ても
何の反応もねえもん
So it looks like I can't call those guys my comrades.
どうやら 俺は
あいつらの仲間じゃないみたいだ
So I'm...
だったら お前らと…
I'm sticking with you guys to rack up some achievements and get rich!
お前らについてって 手柄を立てて
大金持ちになってやる！
Sheesh...
（信）…たく 死んでも知らねえぞ
You might die, ya know.
（貂）黒卑村(こくひむら)の河了貂(かりょうてん)さまが
そう簡単に死ぬかよ ハハハッ…
Lord He Liao Diao of Heibei Village cannot be killed so easily!
At Zhugui Gate, we'll confiscate their weapons and let only the Mountain King and one attendant through.
（江）
あの朱亀(しゅき)の門で武器を取り上げ
山の王と従者１人だけを通します
王自ら赴いているので―
The king is personally agreeing to it, so I don't think they have any underhanded schemes planned,
たくらみなどは
ないとは思いますが
but if there is any such thing, it will happen there.
何かあるとしたら あそこでしょう
ですから
万が一の場合にも抜かりないよう
So there are no mistakes in any such unlikely case,
衛兵は多めに配置しております
（竭氏）うむ…
we have stationed many guards there.
They're confiscating our weapons?!
なっ… 武器を取り上げるって？
（バジオウ）そうだ
Yes.
Then we can't fight, can we?!
それじゃ 戦えねえじゃねえかよ
Exactly.
そのとおりだ
（信）えっ…
だから そこが開戦の場所だ
That is why... the battle will start there!
（竭氏）
見ろ！ 山の民のお出ましだ
Look. The Mountain People have appeared.
Looks like this is gonna be one flashy start to a battle.
こりゃ 派手な開戦になりそうだな
（貂）ひょ… ひょっとして
もう始まるのか？
D-Do you think it's gonna start already?
そうだ
（貂）マズイよ…
Yeah!
This isn't good! They've got twice as many people as we do!
向こうは こっちの倍は いるよ
（信）関係ねえ
Doesn't matter!
Hold on a second, Xin!
ちょっと待ってくれ 信
It's... hard to breathe...
息が… 苦しくて… うまく歩けない
I can barely walk..
貂 俺から絶対 離れんじゃねえぞ
分かったか？
Diao! No matter what, don't drift away from me! Got that?!
G-Got it!
わ… 分かった　絶対に離れない
I-I definitely won't leave you!
Mountain People! Surrender your weapons here!
（衛兵長）
山の民よ！ ここで武器を預かる
全員 武装を解かれよ
Everyone, lay down your arms!
Hey! What?!
（衛兵）おい… 何だ？
（衛兵）様子が変だぞ
They're acting strangely!
（戦士）ンンッ…
（バジオウ）ダメだ
No.
The one most suited to make the first strike in this battle is...
（バジオウ）
この戦の第１刃にふさわしいのは…
（衛兵長）何じゃ？ 貴様ら
What is going on with you guys?!
him!
（バジオウ）ただひとり
C-Chancellor...!
じょ… 丞相 これは一体…
What is going on...?!
丞相？
（竭氏）ンンッ…
Chancellor?
What are you monkeys doing?!
何のマネじゃ 猿ども！
殺せ！ 殺せ！ 皆殺しだ！
Kill! Kill them!
Kill them all!
A bloodbath!
血祭りだ！
Xin!
（貂）信！
Let's go, Diao!
いくぞ 貂！
（貂）お… おう！
R-Right!
丞相… ここは ひとまず奥へ避難を
（竭氏）慌てるな
Chancellor, you should take shelter inside for now!
Do not panic.
That Yang Duan He... how dare he deceive me!
楊端和め　よくも
このわしに一杯食わせおった
じゃが 朱亀の門を甘く見たな？
山猿ども！
But you've underestimated the Zhugui Gate, you mountain monkeys!
（貂･信）ウワッ！
What's going on, Brother Bi?!
どうなってんだ？ 壁のあんちゃん
The Zhugui Gate is built very sturdily, so unless you throw many heavy stones at it, it won't break down!
朱亀の門は 投石機でも使わないと
破壊できないくらい―
頑丈にできているんだ
That's why they chose this place!
（壁）
だから ヤツらは ここを選んだ
（斬る音）
（兵士）バケモンか こいつら！
Are these guys monsters?!
Don't recklessly climb the walls!
むやみに壁を登るな！
狙われるぞ！
They'll target you!
だってよ 門が壊せねえなら―
But...!
If we can't destroy the gate,
壁を越えて
内側から開けるしかねえだろう！
the only thing we can do is climb over the walls and open it from the other side, right?!
Exactly!
（壁）そのとおりだ
だが あの壁は ひと駆けでは
絶対に届かない高さになっている
But those walls are so tall that you'll never get up them in one bound!
じゃ どうすんだよ？
（壁）それは…
Then what do we do?!
Well...
Form a base close to the wall! Form a human ladder and cross over it!
壁際に拠点を作れ！
人バシゴを作って 壁を越えよ！
Lord! At this rate, we're just going to lose more men!
殿！ このままでは
犠牲が増えるばかりです
I know.
（昌文君）分かっている
だが ほかに手はない
But we have no other choice!
Don't falter!
ひるむな！
壁を越えずば 我らに勝利はない！
Unless we cross over that wall, we'll never have victory!
Jiang, choosing Zhugui Gate as the checking station
（竭氏）江よ
関所に朱亀の門を選んだことと―
兵を増やしたことが功を奏したな
（江）はい
and increasing the number of soldiers seems to have been a wise decision.
Yes, sir.
Gather guards behind them.
ヤツらの背後に 衛兵を集結させろ
We'll kill them all in front of the gate!
（竭氏）門前で皆殺しだ！
（戦士）ウウッ…
（貂）ヒイッ…
It's no good! We failed, Xin!
（貂）ダメだ　失敗だよ 信
門を抜けられないんじゃ―
If we can't get through the gate,
there's no point in fighting in a place like this!
こんな所で斬り合っても
意味がないよ
I've gotta do it...
やるっきゃねえ…
（貂）えっ？
I've got to!
やるっきゃねえんだ！
Another one's going for it!
（衛兵２）
また１人 駆け上がるぞ！
That's reckless! Come back, Xin!
（壁）ムチャだ！ 戻れ 信！
That's a wall the Mountain People couldn't reach the top of!
（壁）山の民でも届かぬ壁だぞ！
オリャー！
信！
（吹き矢の音）
Xin!
That hurt, dammit!
痛(いて)えな こらぁ！
と… と… 届いた！
He-He made it!
Outta the way! Leave him to me!
（衛兵２）どけ！ 俺に任せろ！
Oh no! Cover Xin!
いかん！ 信を援護だ！
Die!
死ね！
ハッ… マズッ！
Uh-oh!
I hit him.
当たった
Wh...
なにー！
Whaaaat?!
ヘヘッ… どうだ 見たか！
Did ya see that?
（信）
オッ！ でっけえ おっさんがいるぜ
There's a huge old man up here.
Kill that little monkey!
あの子猿を殺せ！
Ooh, here they come.
（信）ああ 来た来た　遅えっての
Took 'em long enough.
Sorry.
悪いな　漂の弔い合戦兼ねてっから
容赦しねえぞ
This is also my battle to avenge Piao, so I'm not gonna go easy on you.
ハアーッ！
kowaresou na kokoro tsumugu youni
壊れそうな心 紡ぐように
To weave together my breaking heart
yume no kakera mitsume (No more cry)
夢のカケラ見つめ (No more cry）
I gaze at the fragments of a dream (No more crying)
me no mae ni wa tsuki ga utsushidasu
目の前には月が映し出す
The moon I see before my eyes
kono mune no yakusoku
この胸の約束
reflects this promise in my heart
namida ga nokoshita kioku sae mo
涙が残した記憶さえも
I won't turn away from my tearful memories
waraiatta kako sae furimukanai
笑いあった過去さえ振り向かない
nor the past where we laughed together
Voice of soul
Voice of you
kanashimi nara kitto tsuyosa ni kawaru hazu
悲しみならきっと 強さに変わるはず
Sadness is sure to turn into strength
I won't cry
I won't fear
I won't stop
takaku tobeba kitto sora no mukou ni todoku
高く翔べばきっと空の向こうに届く
If I jump high enough, I'm sure I'll reach beyond the sky
Voice of mine
Yeah
Voice of soul
～♪
Preview
We'll enter the inner sanctuary and kill Chengjiao!
（壁）
我らで 本殿にいる成蟜を討つ！
Everyone's lives and resolves clash!
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）それぞれの命と覚悟が
ぶつかり合う　立ち止まるな 信！
Don't stop, Xin!
The Fierce Fighting Begins
Next time,
次回 “激戦 開始”
The Fierce Fighting Begins
End